Antonia Krefeld-Schwalb

Assistant Professor, Rotterdam School of Management, Erasmus University, Rotterdam, Netherlands +31 618 52 44 18 - krefeldschwalb@rsm.nl - www.antoniakrefeldschwalb.com

2016 - 2020	Ph.D., Marketing and Management, University of Geneva.
	Supervisor: Prof. Benjamin Scheibehenne.
	Title: Relevant consumer research: prediction, explanation, and replication.
2012 - 2015	Ph.D., Social Psychology, University of Bern.
	Supervisor: Profs. Margit Oswald and Karl Christoph Klauer.
	Title: The Influence of the Ease of Mental Imagery on Source Memory and Item
	Memory

2010 - 2012 MSc, Psychology, University of Bern 2007 - 2010 BSc, Psychology, University of Hamburg

Employment

Education

since 2021	Assistant Professor, Rotterdam School of Management, Erasmus University,
	Rotterdam, Netherlands
2019 - 2021	Postdoctoral Researcher, Center for Decision Sciences, Columbia Business
	School, Columbia University.
	Supervisor: Eric J. Johnson

Research Interests

I study the impact of individual differences on responses to marketing and policy measures to improve targeting and segmentation. My substantive focus is on sustainable consumer behavior and how to make persuasive messages such as emails and text messages as well as incentives more effective. I also investigate methodological problems to improve the validity of preference measurements and the generalizability of experimental methods in consumer research.

Publications

- 1. Krefeld-Schwalb, A., Sugerman E. & Johnson, E.J. (2024). Exposing omitted moderators: Explaining why effect sizes differ in the social sciences. Proceedings of the National Academy of Science, 121 (12). https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2306281121
- 2. Krefeld-Schwalb, A., & Scheibehenne, B. (2023). Tighter nets for smaller fishes: Mapping the development of statistical practices in consumer research between 2008 and 2020. Marketing Letters, 34, 351–36. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11002-022-09662-3
- 3. Li, Y.*, Krefeld-Schwalb, A.*, Wall, D. G., Johnson, E. J., Toubia, O., & Bartels, D. M. (2022). The More You Ask, the Less You Get: When Additional Questions Hurt External Validity. Journal of Marketing Research, 59(5), 963-982. https://doi.org/10.1177/00222437211073581 [*Shared first authorship]

- 4. Krefeld-Schwalb, A., Scheibehenne, B., & Pachur, T. (2022). Structural Parameter Interdependencies in Computational Models of Cognition. Psychological Review, 129(2), 313–339. https://doi.org/10.1037/rev0000285
- 5. Krefeld-Schwalb, A., & Rosner, A. (2020). A new way to guide consumer's choice: Retro-cueing alters the availability of product information in memory. Journal of Business Research, 111, 135–147. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jbusres.2019.08.012
- 6. Krefeld-Schwalb, A., Donkin, C., Newell, B. R., & Scheibehenne, B. (2019). Empirical comparison of the adjustable spanner and the adaptive toolbox models of choice. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory, and Cognition, 45(7), 1151–1165. https://doi.org/10.1037/xlm0000641
- Krefeld-Schwalb, A., Witte, E. H., & Zenker, F. (2018). Hypothesis-Testing Demands Trustworthy Data — A Simulation Approach to Inferential Statistics Advocating the Research Program Strategy. Frontiers in Psychology, 9(March), 1–14. https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2018.00460
- 8. Krefeld-Schwalb, A. (2018). The Retro-Cue Benefit for Verbal Material and Its Influence on the Probability of Intrusions Under Dual-Task Conditions. Experimental Psychology, 65(3), 128–138. https://doi.org/10.1027/1618-3169/a000400
- 9. Krefeld-Schwalb, A., Ellis, A. W., & Oswald, M. E. (2015). Source memory for mental imagery: Influences of the stimuli's ease of imagery. PLoS ONE, 10(11), 1–14. https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0143694.

Research in Progress

Sustainable Consumer Behavior

- 1. Krefeld-Schwalb, A.*, Gabel, S. * Wei, S.*. Global evidence for motives underlying sustainable behaviors. https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/syku6 . [* Equal Contribution]
- 2. Gabel, S.* & Krefeld-Schwalb, A.* Sustainable future: Fostering sustainable behavior with targeted interventions. https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/nc2bh [* Equal Contribution]

Relevance and Generalizability of Consumer Research

- 3. Krefeld-Schwalb, A., Constantino, S. & Paolacci, G. (RR at Journal of Marketing). The evidence you see is all there is: Selective reporting in applied market research.
- 4. Sugerman, E., Krefeld-Schwalb, A. & Johnson E. (in preparation). From reproducibility crisis to generality revolution in consumer research.

Preference Measurement

- 5. Krefeld-Schwalb, A., Bartels, D., Johnson, E.J.. More than money over time: Consumers' intertemporal preferences for money, health and getting things done. https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/8d2w4
- 6. Krefeld-Schwalb, A & Johnson, E.J. (in preparation). Ensembled Preference.

Search Processes in Consumer Choice

- 7. Krefeld-Schwalb, A., Martinovici, A., Orquin, J. L., Aribarg, A., Bhatia, S., Erdem, T., ... Yang, C. L. (RR at the International Journal of Research in Marketing). Search in service of choice. https://doi.org/10.31234/osf.io/xw5bv
- 8. Reeck, C., Lee, B. C., Krefeld-Schwalb, A., Xu, S. & Johnson, E.J.. (under Review at Management Science). Information search shapes consumer patience: A novel process model for intertemporal choice.

Invited Talks

Booth School of Business, University of Chicago (2024), Technical University Delft (2024), Tilburg University (2024), Ludwig Maximilian University, Munich (2024), Wharton Business School, University of Pennsylvania (2023), Princeton University (2023), Pompeu Fabre (2023), University of Warwick (2022), Uppsala University (2022), Maastricht University (2022), University of St.Gallen (2020), Rotterdam School of Management (2020), TUM School of Management (2020), Boğaziçi University Istanbul (2019), Columbia University (2019), University of Zürich (2018), Max-Planck-Institute of Human Development (2018)

Teaching Experience

Year	Title	Program	Evaluations
2023-2024	Noise: Understanding Errors in Human Judgement and Prediction Task: Design and Delivery of the entire course	MSc Marketing, Rotterdam School of Management	5/5 (°24), 5/5 (°23).
2021-2024	Going viral: Ideas that spread around the world Task: Design and Delivery of the entire course	BA/IBA, Rotterdam School of Management	3.9/5 ('23), 4.2/5 ('22), 4/5 ('21).
2022-2024	Living Management Project, Task: Supervising student groups working on consultancy projects No individual teaching evaluation	MBA, Rotterdam School of Management	No individual evaluation
2022-2024	Consumer Behavior Task: Teach one session about research around preference measurement. Each session is taught by a different faculty member.	PhD, Rotterdam School of Management	No individual evaluation
2018	Introduction to R Task: Teaching one out of three days on specific functions and packages in R for data presentation and programming of web applications, the remaining two days were held by Benjamin Scheibehenne.	PhD, University of Geneva	No individual evaluation
2016-2017	Consumer Behavior I Task: Teaching multiple sessions and preparation of the exam, the remaining	BSc Economics and Management, <i>University of Geneva</i>	4/4

	sessions were held by Benjamin Scheibehenne		
2016-2018	Consumer Behavior II Task: Preparation of the exam, the sessions were held by Benjamin Scheibehenne	BSc Economics and Management, <i>University of Geneva</i>	3.8/4
2017	Consumer Research Task: The course is split in a practical and a theoretical part, I taught the practical part which is an introduction to R and the theoretical part was taught by Benjamin Scheibehenne	MSc Management, University of Geneva	3.7/4
2016-2019	Food Marketing, Task: Correction, grading, and preparation of weekly homework and in- class presentation, the sessions were held by Benjamin Scheibehenne	BSc Economics and Management, <i>University of Geneva</i>	No individual evaluation
2015	False memories, Task: Conceptualization and teaching of the entire course	BSc Psychology, <i>University</i> of Freiburg	
2015	Decision making, Task: Conceptualization and teaching of the entire course	BSc Psychology, University of Freiburg	
2013	Empirisches Praktikum, Task: Conceptualization and teaching of the entire course	BSc Psychology, University of Bern	

Thesis Supervision

2021- 2023	10 master theses as main supervisor and 10 master theses as co-reader per year
2019	Master thesis, Management, University of Geneva
2017	2 Bachelor theses, Psychology, University of Freiburg
2014- 2016	3 Bachelor theses and 3 Master theses, Psychology, University of Bern

Individual Scientific Reviewing Activities

Management Science, Journal of Marketing Research, Journal of Marketing, Psychological Review, PNAS, Decision, Computational Brain and Behavior, Journal of Business Research, Journal of Experimental Psychology: Learning, Memory and Cognition, Judgment and Decision Making

Third-Party Funding and Awards

2024	Seed Grant, Convergence - Resilient Delta Initiative, EUR 326,000 Role: Grant Applicant and Project lead with Sebastain Gabel and Tatiana Filatova
2024	Veni Grant, NWO Dutch Research Council (Nederlandse Organisatie voor
	Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek), EUR 320,000
	Role: Grant Applicant
2023	Various in-kind product sponsors, ~ EUR 30,000
	(https://sustainability.rsm.nl/demo)
2023	Kickstarter grant, Convergence Initiative, EUR 29,954
	Role: Grant Applicant together with Sebastian Gabel

2023	Humboldt Residency Program: Our Precious Resources: Wege zu einer sicheren und nachhaltigen Zukunft, Alexander von Humboldt Stiftung
2019	PostDoc mobility Scholarship, Swiss National Science Foundation, CHF 197,000
	Role: Grant Applicant.
2017	Project Grant, Swiss National Science Foundation, CHF 239,721
	Role: Conceptualization of the research plan and writing of the application.
	Grant applicant: Benjamin Scheibehenne; Project Partner: Thorsten Pachur
2017	Travel Grant, Société Académique Genève
	Role: Grant applicant
2016	Travel Grant, Schweizerische Akademie der Geistes- und Sozialwissenschaften
	Role: Grant applicant
2016	Student Award, Society for Mathematical Psychology
2015	Doc mobility Scholarship, Swiss National Science Foundation, CHF 40,255